

David Sanchez

(Jose David Sanchez Aguilar) Helping people to build the most innovative solutions with technology.

USA Permanent Resident & Costa Rica citizen.

Orlando, Florida, USA 🙃

Mobile: +1 (425) 326-7927 \$\

Email: dsanchezcr@outlook.com ≥

LinkedIn Profile in

GitHub Profile 🗘

Sessionize (Public Speaking)

Personal Website & Bloq @



Computer Systems Engineer with over 13 years of experience in the Information Technology industry focused on consulting for software engineering and cloud adoption with experience in multiple disciplines (Engineering, Sales, Consulting and Marketing).

Award: Microsoft Most Valuable Professional - Developer Technologies 2013, 2014, 2015, 2023.

Skills

Tools & Technologies

- Microsoft Azure
- Visual Studio
- Azure DevOps
- GitHub (GHEC & GHES)
- .NET & C#
- SQL (MS SQL/SQL Azure)
- HTML5 (CSS & JS)
- Power Platform
- SharePoint & Office 365

Industry Knowledge

- DevOps & Agile
- Technical Training
- Consultancy
- Content Strategery
- Sales Management
- Localization & Translation
- Identity & Access
- Program Management
- FinOps: Cloud Economics

Interpersonal (Soft Skills)

- Active Listening
- Public Speaking
- Time Management
- Leadership
- Mentoring
- People Management
- Conflict Resolution
- Communication
- Critical Thinking

Certifications

Microsoft



















GitHub









Linux Foundation





Languages

Spanish: Native.

English: Fluent.

Portuguese: Limited.

Experience

SEP 2022 - NOV 2023

DevOps Consultant / Xebia | Xpirit Orlando, FL, USA.

I was the second technical hired and the sixth employee of Xebia | Xpirit in USA. I have been in charge of supporting sales with pre-sales activities such as scoping projects, creating statements of work (SOWs) and presenting proposals to customers. Consulting and service delivery by leading and managing projects, in addition to creating technical content, blog posts, webinars, in-person event sessions and magazine articles as part of the company's core values for Sharing Knowledge.

Xebia | Xpirit is a Microsoft Gold Partner and GitHub Verified Partner that started in Netherlands in 2014 and expanded to USA in July of 2022. I joined a team of highly skilled and experienced consultants, experts in Microsoft Azure and DevOps. As part of our projects and services, I am a vendor contractor for GitHub & Microsoft. Accredited & certified in GitHub Professional Services.

OCT 2021 - SEP 2022

Senior Technical Program Manager / Microsoft Corp Redmond, WA, USA.

Owned the Spanish and Portuguese localization & consumption of content for Microsoft Learn.

APR 2021 - OCT 2021

Senior Developer Advocate / Microsoft Corp

Redmond, WA, USA.

Responsible for creating and presenting technical content for Azure Maps and its Geospatial APIs.













JAN 2018 - APR 2021

Technical Product Marketing Manager / Microsoft Corp Redmond, WA, USA.

I helped defining and creating a set of end-to-end sample applications focused on Microsoft Azure services for developers. Drove an agile process for demo development with multiple cross-team collaboration for major Microsoft events and keynotes, supporting the demos delivering, executive speaker support, on-stage presentation, and open-source maintenance. Worked broadly across Microsoft Azure engineering, marketing, and field stakeholders to create content.









FEB 2017 - DEC 2017

Consultant - Application Development Manager / Microsoft San Jose, Costa Rica.

Technical delivery for Premier Support for Developers providing end-to-end managed support across the full Microsoft developer platform: on-premises, hybrid or in the cloud.

DEC 2015 - JAN 2017

Sales Solution Professional / Microsoft

San Jose, Costa Rica.

Technical pre-sales solutions for Microsoft Developer Tools and Technologies including Visual Studio Product Suite, Team Foundation Server, VSTS (Azure DevOps) and Microsoft Azure.

AUG 2012 - PRESENT

Microsoft Certified Trainer / Advance Learning San Jose, Costa Rica.

I deliver Microsoft Official Courses to customers for Microsoft Azure & Software Engineering.

FEB 2012 - DEC 2015

Consultant – Software Engineering / Multiple Companies San Jose, Costa Rica.

Designed & implemented SharePoint solutions, leveraging SharePoint Server and Online with Office 365 for enhanced productivity and collaboration. Led ALM/DevOps initiatives, optimizing project lifecycle & ensuring top-notch code quality by empowering software engineering teams.

OCT 2010 - JAN 2012

Software Support Engineer / Hewlett-Packard Enterprise San Jose, Costa Rica.

I provided support as Level I & II for three HP Enterprise Software (uCMDB, BSM & SiteScope).

APR 2010 - OCT 2010

Software Developer / Universidad Latina de Costa Rica San Jose, Costa Rica.

Oracle database and developer in charge of optimizing internal reports and processes.

Education

2013 - 2015 (FINISHED COURSES - UNGRADUATED)

Master Information Technology Management Universidad para la Cooperación Internacional San Jose, Costa Rica.

2008 - 2011 (GRADUATED)

Bachelor Computer Systems Engineering Universidad Latina de Costa Rica San Jose, Costa Rica.